Guide to the Robert J. Havighurst Papers 1921-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: General Education
  - Teaching the Scientific Attitude (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous MS (1 of 2) (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous MS (2 of 2) (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - General Education at the College Level (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Biblio, Outline (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Guidance-Miscellaneous MS, Outlines, Corpts (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Science ED-MS, Notes, Correspondence (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Science ED-MS, Correspondence, Outlines (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - MS-Science Teaching in America (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Intro to Physical Science, 1930 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Intro to Phys Science, 1931 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Science Ed (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Diary-Ohio State University, 1932-1934 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Ohio State Univ. Lab School, 1932-1934 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Appraisal of the General Ed. Program (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Gen Ed Program (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Appraisal of the Gen. Ed. Program #2 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Periodical Study (1 of 2) (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Periodical Study (2 of 2) (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Public Opinion Study of Youth and Education, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Fosdiak-Havinghurst Correspondnece re:Program in Gen Ed, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Gen Ed Seminar (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Child Study Program-General Education Board (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - American Youth Congress (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Study of Needs (1 of 2) (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Study of Needs (2 of 2) (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report of the GE Board, 1936-1937 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Ann. Report (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report of the GE Board, 1939 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Preliminary Report on the Program in Gen Ed, 1933-1940 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Appendices II, III and V to Preliminary Report on the Program in Gen. Ed. (Box 43, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Child Development and Adolescence
  - Appendix IV to Preliminary Report on the Program in Gen. Ed. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Report on a Study of American Education (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Buchanan, Scott. In Search of a Liberal College (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Harvard University Committee on General Ed, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Harvard Science Program (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Vocational Ed (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Character Studies (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Psych. Of Moral Character-Correspondence (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Summary Rosters, Aptitude Tests- T42, T45 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - 12.01 Summary Rosters, Aptitude Tests-T42 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - 12.04 Summary Rosters, 1945 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Criterion Studies (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Confidential Checklist of Personal Characteristics (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Life Problems and Student Beliefs (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Family and Character (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Moral Development (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Dallas (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Moral Development Transparencies (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Moral Development-1982 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Character Education (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Adolescent Character and Personality (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Religious Education (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Religious Youth Culture (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Responsibility (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - McCormick Theological Seminary, April 28-29, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Religious Ed. Material (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - NSSE Yearbook on Youth Book Reviews (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Hartford Seminary (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Lin, William T. (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Youth (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence on Youth (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Jobs for Youth (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Satisfaction with Work (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Work Values (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Work (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Evelyn Brandon’s Interviews (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Moral Character (Box 47, Folder 2)
- Series V: Society and Education
  - Early Schooling, Dangers of (1 of 3) (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Early Schooling, Dangers of (2 of 3) (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Early Schooling, Dangers of (3 of 3) (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Univ. of AL Pay Document (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - "Federal Stimulus and Executive Leadership: A Study of Early Childhood Education Policy Making in Georgia" (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Alaska-Moore (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - AERA Symposium (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Gifted Child Book (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Grost, Mike (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Personality of the Gifted (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Evanston-Gifted Child (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - ED 338-Bibl. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - ED 338-Outline and Rdgs (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - ED 338-Pamphlets on Education Of the Gifted (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Lectures on the Gifted Child (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Creativity (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Gifted Children-Miscellaneous MS (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Slides-Hyperactivity (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Hyperactive Children (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Drugs for Hyperactive Children (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Choosing a Middle Path for the Use of Drugs with Hyperactive Children, Nov 1976 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - AAAS Boston Mtg., Feb 18-24, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Hyperactive Children (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Drugs for Hyperactive Children (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Hyperactive Children-Correspondence (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Korbus Family-MS, Jan 1944 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Korbus Family-Miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Admare, Dick (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Admare-Complete (1 of 3) (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Admare-Complete (2 of 3) (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Admare-Complete (3 of 3) (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Family Studies (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Notes (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Background Material (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Admare Family (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Elno Families (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Separate Family Members-Korbus (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Admare Family (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Vallone (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Higher Education (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Higher Education in the 1970s (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, MS, Clippings, Correspondence (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Clippings, Correspondence (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Davis-Ells Test of General Intelligence or Problem-Solving Ability (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Rehage, Kenneth J. (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Adams County Sr. Citizens Council (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Adolescence (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - "A Cross-Cultural View of Adolescence" (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - MS Chapter-Youth and Adolescence (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - "Mental Health and Adolescence: Adolescent Identity and the Transition fro Adolescence to Early Childhood," Aug, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Varieties of Youth (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Androgyny (1 of 2) (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Androgyny (2 of 2) (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - "A Demographic Perspective on Action Learning" (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Cultural Pluralism (1 of 2) (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Cultural Pluralism (2 of 2) (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Australian Aborigines and Anglo Culture (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Ovando, Carlos J. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Poverty (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Catholic Schools (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Adolescence and Cultural Pluralism (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Youth Culture and Subculture (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Anglo vs. Native Culture (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Cultural Pluralism-Miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Chicago Heights (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Minority Subcultures and the Laws of Learning (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - "The Park Forest Problem," March 1967 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Suburban Youth (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Gladstein, Gerald A. Original Data Sheets for Projective and Cultural Factors in an Experimental Test of Intelligence (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Education and Society (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Anglo vs. Native Cultures-Miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Studies of Children and Society in N.Z. (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - O’Shea, David. "Suburban Community Socio-Economic Status and School District Operative Expenditures" (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Social Psychology of Adolescence (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - "Education Without Schools: 12 Years of It" March, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Child Rearing (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Adolescence-Miscellaneous Ms. (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Eastern Europe (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Board of Education Survey (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Teaching Bilingual Eskimo Children, July 28, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - ED 318 B, Human Development in both Childhood and Early Adolescence (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Social Status, Peer Status, and Social Mobility (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - ED 311 and 323 materials (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - ED 338-The Gifted Child (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - HD 314-1963 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - ED 311-The Growth and Development of Adolescence (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographies for Teaching (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Notes on HD (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - ED 323-Metropolitan Development and the Educational System (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Course Materials-Miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Clippings (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Exam Questions (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - ED and Social Order-Exam Questions (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - ED 317 Educational Sociology (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - ED and Social Order-Miscellaneous (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - ED 317-ED Sociology-Exams (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous-Notes, Course, Materials, MS (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Physical Living Space (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - ED 419: Social Stratification, HD 351: Social Inst. (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Education and Stratification (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Education and Miscellaneous MS (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - ED and Emergent Soc. (1 of 3) (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - ED and Emergent Soc. (2 of 3) (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - ED and Emergent Soc. (3 of 3) (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Society and Education (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Education and the Great Society, Sept 1966 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Ed and Great Society (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Oxford UP (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Disadvantaged Children, 1968-1970 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Socially Disadvantaged Youth, 1960-1967 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Waukegan Armstrong Act Case, 1966 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Educationally Deprived and Disadvantaged Youth, 1965-1975 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Society and Education (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - "The Crisis for Integration in American Education," April 1967 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Dissertation/M.A. Abstracts (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - School and Culturally Deprived Youth, 1966 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - PhD Abstract, 1966 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Culturally Deprived Youth, 1961-1964 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Psychological Dimensions of Cultural Poverty and Culturally Deprived Youth (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography for Conference on Research Problems of Education and Cultural Deprivation, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Study of Cognitive Environments of Urban Pre-School Children (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Social Class Influence, 1957-1961 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Culturally Deprived-Other Writers, 1966-1974 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Research in Cultural Deprivation (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - "Strengthening Family Life for Children: The School and the Family," May 28, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Bernstein, Basil n.d. (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, MS, Correspondence, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Scheer, James F., 1982 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Dissertation Abstract: "Maternal Behavior and Language and Concept Formation in Negro Pre-School Children: An Inquiry into Process," n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous MS Notes, Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Zach, Miriam S. MA Paper: "The Development of Federal Policy Toward Handicapped Persons," June 25,1980 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Cultural Parity, 1962-1971 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - UNESCO Study, 1965-1970 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - UNESCO Study, on Disadvantaged Children, 1965-1970 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - UNESCO, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Society and Education, 1964-1968 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Social Class and Health, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Social Class, 1945-1958 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Values and Social Class (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Social Mobility and Soc. Integration, 1946-1965 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Social Class Perspectives on the Life Cycle, 1970-1972 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Guidelines for School Data and Records, 1970-4 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Ethics and Social Science, 1971-1977 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Conflicts in Educational Sociology, 1976-1977 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Teacher-Child Relationships, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - ED 321/HD 412 Social Status and Learning, 1955-1962 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - HD 412, Social Class and Socialization thru the Life Span, Rdg. List (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Memos, 1963-1964 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Flaugher, Ronald L. "Project Access Research Report #3: Minority vs. Majority Group Performance on an Aptitude Test Battery," 1971 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - "Minority Subcultures and the Laws of Learning," 1969-1970 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Collective Bargaining (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Nation’s Schools, May 1972 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, MS, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Teachers and Politics, 1973 (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - "Teaching Profession," Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Tables (Box 59, Folder 19)
  - "The Social Basis of Human Development," n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Child Socialization (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous MS and Correspondence, 1974 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Soc. Mobility-MS, Grant Proposal, 1958 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Social Mobility, 1964-1965 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Individual in Society, 1945-1950, ANTH 390/SOC 390 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Social Loyalty and Citizenship, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Social Roles of the Elderly, 1955-1963 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Social Roles, 1951-1958 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Social Mobility Tables (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Social Stratification-Biblios, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Social Stratification, 1941-1959 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Social Class, Marriage and Family, 1950-1959 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Social Mobility-Miscellaneous (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Social Status and Education, 1948-1953 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Social Class and Education, 1943-1967 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Syllabus, 1963 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Social Mobility and Education, 1959-1975 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Educational and Occupational Distribution in the US, April 1949 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Packard, Vance. The Status Seekers. Bulletin, Review. (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Index of Status Characteristics, 1953-1964 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - ISC Study, 1955 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - ED 317, Case Studies, 1942 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Brandon, Evelyn, 1943-1944 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Case Studies, 1942 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Case Studies, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - LANG Trial, 1950-1952 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Survey of 9th Grade Students, Feb 1944 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Survey of 9th Grade Students, May 1944 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Rebecca E. Carroll, Survey of Middle-Class African-American Students in Baltimore, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Cooperative Community Research Plans, 1951-1955 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Cooperative Community Research Plan, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Doll, Russell Charles. "A Sociological Comparison of Ninth and Twelfth Grade, White and Negro Students in a Suburban High School," MA (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Education in the Big City-Bibliography, ED 323, 1961 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Book Reviews, 1951-1963 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Charts and Tables, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Course Materials, 1947-1960 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Great Cities Improvement Program, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Population Growth Among Negro Citizens in KC, MO, May 1967 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Course Materials, 1962-1969 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Education and Subcultures, Miscellaneous CM (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Implications of Educational Changes and Resource Trends for Urban Planners, Jan 1970 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Urban Development and Ed-Miscellaneous MS, 1960-1962 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - The Crisis in Urban Ed., 1970 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Urban Education, 1966-1969 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Urban Education, 1968-1970 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Course Materials, 1967 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous MS and Notes, 1963-1966 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous MS, Notes, Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Urban School Admin, 1960-1979 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Metropolitan Development and Educational Facilities, April 1966 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, clippings, ms, tables (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous MS, 1961-1966 (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Bibl, MS, Notes, Course Materials, 1960-1961 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Urban Education (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Course Materials, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - The Evolution and Megalopolis and its Concomitants, Oct 1960 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Clippings, 1961 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - City-School Cooperation in Developing Educational Policy and Practice, September 1965 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Emerging Urban Problems and Their (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Tables of High School Study, Harvey, IL, by Al Lucco and R. Doll, 9/8/61 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Urban Renewal, 1961-1972 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Metropolitan Social Systems, 1961-1965 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Board of Ed-Correspondence And Notes, 1966-1969 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - "Education and the Social Problems of the Big City," Dec 30, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Urban Dynamics, 1962-1963 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Education and Metropolitanism, 1961-1966 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Course Mats, Notes, Correspondence (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Cemrd, Inc., 1978 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Urban Education, 68-79 (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Notes, 68-69 (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - Nat’l Assn of Secondary School Principals, 64-79 (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, Notes, 6B (Box 64, Folder 17)
  - Sizemore, Barbara A., "The History of a Negro Family’s Migration to Evanston," n.d. (Box 64, Folder 18)
  - Bussing in U. City, MO, 69-70 (Box 64, Folder 19)
  - Levine, Daniel U., Albers, Sharon and Knego, Robert H., "The Community Context of School Desegregation in a Midwestern City," Dec 1969 (Box 64, Folder 20)
  - Lowe, Francis Y., 1970 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Service Learning, 75 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - American Youth in the mid-70s, 72-78 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Nat’l Commission on Resources for Youth (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Service Learning, 75-81 (1-2) (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - A Major Program of Action-Learning for Youth (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Action-Learning and Demography of Youth, 68-79 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Conference on American Youth in the mid-70s, 1972 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Action-Learning, Minneapolis-St. Paul, 72-75 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous MS, 1943-1968 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Youth in the 60s, 1966-68 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - "Education and Turbulent Youth," Sept 1966 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Alienated Youth, 67-75 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - John Casparis and Edmund W. Van, Swiss Family, Society and Youth Culture, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Youth and Adulthood, 59-75 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Adolescent Subculture, 78 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous MS, Correspondence, Notes, 59-71 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - James S. Coleman, "Inequality, Sociology, and Moral Phil.", 1972 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Youth Values, 67-69 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Conservatism in Education, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous MS, 68-69 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous MS, Notes, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - The Bases of Healthy Behavior, Sept 1976 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Schools and Disaffected Youth, 1976 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - The Youth Crisis and the Community College, April 4, 1975 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - ED 323-Miscellaneous MS, 1960 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Alienated Youth: A Statement of National Policy, Dec 1960 (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Adolescence-Miscellaneous MS, 1963-1966 (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous MS, 1961-1981 (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - College and Youth, 1972-1974 (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Youth and Work, 1974-1981 (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Youth, 1968-1980, Notes, Correspondence and MS (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - "School and Adolescence," Aug 1959 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Educational Reform, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Marriage, Education and Youth Values, 46-52 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Developmental Tasks and Adolescence, 49-60 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Guidance and Counseling, 1963-1965 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Definitions of Sociological Terms, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Discipline for Children, 48-49 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Sr. Center for Creative Activities in Marin County, 1981-1983 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - "Educational Changes and their Implications for Libraries," March 1967 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Education and Society, 1967 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Humanist Education, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Arts and Education, 1957-1970 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Youth Employment, 1974-1980 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Job Satisfaction, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Blue Gargoyle Youth Service Center, 1981-1983, Correspondence (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Women and Labor, 1976 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Youth Project, 1979-1980 (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Work and Society, 1970 (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Ethnomethodology, 1970 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Marginal Youth, 1964-1965 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - IL Youth Commission, 1964-1965 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 61-65 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Education of Disadvantaged Children, 69-75 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Drop-Outs and Potential Drop-Outs, 1962-1964 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Robert Rosenbluth, "Proposal for a Summer School Program in the War on Poverty," June 1965 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Robert Martin Rian, "Student-Tutoring Projects: A Psycho-Sociological Analysis," n.d. (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - The Action People, 1968 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Work-Study Programs, 1962 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Youth and Work, 1960-1965 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Schrag, Peter, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - The Unknown Good: Educational Vouchers, Sept 1970 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Ad-Hoc Committee on State Aid to Non-Public Schools, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous MS, 68-70 (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Lloyd J. Mendelson, "The National Science Foundation and Educational Policy," n.d. (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Civil Rights Survey, July 1964 (Box 68, Folder 17)
  - Dept. of Health, Ed and Welfare, 1969-1972 (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Army Dependents Schools, 1965 (Box 68, Folder 19)
  - "Implications of Current Societal Change for Psychology and Education," Oct 28, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 20)
  - Policy Making for American Public Schools, Oct 1968 (Box 68, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous MS, Notes, Correspondence, Abstracts, 1966-1967 (Box 68, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 23)
  - National Assessment of Ed., n.d. (Box 68, Folder 24)
  - Education and Assessment, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 25)
  - Steps Toward Compensatory ed. in the Chicago Public Schools, Aug 1964 (Box 68, Folder 26)
  - Chicago School Survey, 1964 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Characteristics and Needs of Students that Affect Learning, June 1964 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - The Federal Gov’t and Education, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Southwestern Cooperative Educational Laboratory, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Appalachia Educational Laboratory, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Educational Planning in Developed Countries, 1963 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - "Opportunity, Equity, or Equality through Education," review of "Inequality: A Reassessment of the Effect of Family and Schooling in America," 72-73. (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Book Reviews, 1944-1973 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Conference on Education and Economic Development, April 4-5, 1963 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Education and Economic Development in Underdeveloped Countries, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Education and Economic Development, 1962-1963 (Box 69, Folder 11)